which is larger e to the pi or pi to the
E to figure this out graph the function
y equals the natural log of x over X
this function has a derivative equal to
1 minus the natural log of x over x
squared and this derivative is zero if
and only if x is equal to E
this means that the function attains a
maximum value at x equals e and in
particular that maximum value is 1 over
e
now because Pi is not equal to E when we
plug Pi into the function we get the
value natural log of pi over pi and we
see that this value is less than one
over e
therefore we conclude that the natural
log of pi over Pi is less than one over
e multiply both sides by E and Pi then
apply one natural log rule followed by
another natural log rule at this point
we found our winner calculus has proved
to us that pi to the E is less than e to
the pi
[Music]